# Simon Verhoeven

simonaverhoeven@gmail.com UK and Swiss National +6583630416

04-15 Suites@Katong 263 Tanjong Katong Rd Singapore, 437050

#### **PROFILE**

A keen Software Developer/Consultant with 9 years' experience in IT Professional Services. Driven to learn and dive deep into problems and technologies. Looking for hands-on role working with technologies that excite me. Interested in full stack development, serverless application architecture (such as AWS Lambda) and frontend development (particularly React.js).

#### **SKILLS**

- Frontend JavaScript/TypeScript, React.js, Next.js, D3.js, Web Components (Stencil), Webpack, CSS, Sass
- Backend Node.js, Java (Spring Boot)
- Testing Jest, Puppeteer, Cypress, JUnit, Selenium
- AWS API Gateway, Lambda, Cognito, DynamoDB, EC2, ECS
- DevOps Jenkins, Docker, AWS Cloud Formation (Cloud Development Kit)
- Agile Methodologies Scrum methodology, JIRA
- Web Service Integration SOAP, REST, GraphQL
- Relational and NoSQL Databases Postgres, MySQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB
- Fundamental Computing Skills Windows, Mac, Linux/UNIX, Batch/Shell
- Public Speaking Frequent experience in presenting ideas and technologies to large groups

## WORK EXPERIENCE

Telepathy Labs, Singapore

February 2022 - Current

Senior Software Engineer

- Architect and build several Telepathy Labs software products.
- Technologies; Node.js, React.js, Next.js, TypeScript, Docker, GraphQL.
- Schedule, supervise and delegate tasks among other developers.

Whire (whire.net), Singapore

June 2021 - Current

Chief Technology Officer

- Set the technical direction for product development.
- Manage and oversee all IT related elements of business.

Zühlke, Singapore

July 2020 - January 2022

Expert Software Developer

- Responsible for developing IT architectures of innovative software solutions and for strategic client technology consulting.
- Technologies; Node.js, React.js, TypeScript, Jenkins, Docker, Java (Spring Boot).
- Frontend Capability Owner: Responsible for reviewing technology horizons (key technologies used in current and future projects) and planning learning for developers.
- Conducted initial and final stage interviews.

Appway, Singapore

April 2018 - June 2020

- Senior Architect
  - Involved in every step of the product development life cycle from requirements to training.
  - Designed and implemented several large-scale enterprise applications.
  - Influenced key stakeholders by proposing new and alternative solutions.
  - Supported and maintained production environments.

Appway AG, Zurich

September 2014 - March 2018

- Sustem Architect
  - Designed and built a variety of bespoke IT financial solutions using Appway. A fully Java+HTML-based BPMN<sup>1</sup> engine that outputs interactive web applications based on a given model of a business process.
  - Held management responsibilities including project scope planning and client billing.

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>1</sup>Business Process Model and Notation

#### **PROJECTS**

Stella Platform Portal, Singapore - Admin Portal

- Developed platform for tracking and managing Stella Automotive AI, a digital assistant for car dealerships (handles reception desk and service scheduling lines).
- Technologies; Node.js, Next.js, TypeScript, Jest, Docker, GraphQL, .NET.
- Frontend team lead. Coached team members, delegated tasks, reviewed pull requests.

#### Standard Chartered Bank, Singapore - Internet Banking Application

- Developed features focusing on customer wealth management.
- Technologies; Node.js, React.js, TypeScript, Jest, Cypress, Puppeteer, Jenkins, Docker, Java (Spring Boot), GraphQL.
- Setup processes/tools for frontend and backend teams to create/edit GraphQL schema and mock responses. Presented a new way of working to key decision makers and provided support throughout its adoption.

# Whire (whire.net), Singapore - Web Recruiting Platform

- Designed and implemented entire application architecture.
- Technologies; Node.js, TypeScript, Next.js, GraphQL, AWS Cloud Development Kit, AWS Lambda, ECS, Fargate.

# Julius Baer, Singapore - Portfolio Management Application

- Led workshops with the client to outline business and technical requirements.
- Developed a full stack automated portal for assignment, visualization and filtering of employee work items; JavaScript, SQL.

# Credit Suisse, Zurich - Customer Account Opening Application

- Heavily involved in sprint planning and story creation (using JIRA).
- Implemented customer document generation, integrated with Silanis Esign.
- Implemented integrations to back end systems; SOAP, REST, Oracle, Apache ActiveMQ.
- Best Practices Coordinator; led weekly code reviews to ensure high codebase quality.

# Credit Suisse Trust, Zurich - Trust Structures Management Application

- Responsible for entire application architecture; from concept to development and Go Live.
- Led project scoping meetings (outlining achievable goals within budget).
- Responsible for client billing.
- Integrated the application with multiple web services (SOAP) in 4 global locations.

## **EDUCATION**

#### University of York

2011 - 2014

BEng Computer Science with a year in industry (2:1)

# Bilborough College

2008 - 2010

A-Levels; Mathematics (A), Physics (A), Computing (B)

# TECHNOLOGY INTERESTS

Alpaca Cup (alpacacup.com) - Wakeboard Competition App

- Created a competition management app for event organizers and competitors.
- Serverless web application; AWS Cloud Development Kit, AWS Lambda (Node.js), GraphQL (Apollo), React.js
- Launched in April 2021, has been used to host 17 live competitions.

#### OTHER

Sports

- Wakeboarding, skiing (competed at University level), skydiving, trampolining and cycling.
- Completed a charity bike ride from York to Paris as a team of 5. Raised over £500 for Cancer Research UK.

#### Foreign Languages

• Confident conversational German (CEFR B2 level).

#### REFERENCES

Available on request